Mss.974.811.Ea7
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - ALS to Miss Sarah Wister, 25 August 1845; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 26 July 1848; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 30 August; 4.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Disownment of Wister, Charles from the Religious Society of Friends, 25 November 1803; 1.0 p.; Philadelphia Yearly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends.
  - Bond, 1 May 1809; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Poetry by Charles Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Poetry by Charles Wister, 1814; 1.0 p. fragment; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Poetry by Charles Wister, undated; 1.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Poetry by Charles Wister, undated; 1.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 4 August; 3.0 p.; Wister, Mrs. Charles
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 12 October 1849; 4.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 6 October 1849; 3.0; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 11 October 1842; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 16 September 1842; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - ALS to Susan Wister, 18 September 1842; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - APcS to Hannah Wister, 20 August 1884; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - ALS to [?], 15 November 1802; 4.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - APcS to Daniel Wister, undated; 1.0 p.; Wister, Caudy
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 28 February 1826; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth Harvey
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 11 February 1829; 4.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth Harvey
  - ALS to Ann Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth Harvey
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 19 April; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth Harvey
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 9 August 1816; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth Harvey
  - Journal by Elizabeth Wister, 1783; 23.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 5 August 1799; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 27 December 1805; 4.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 1804; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
    The date of this letter is taken from notes of a previous archivist.
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 15 November 1805; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Hannah Foulke, 1801; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
    The date of this letter is taken from a precious archivist's note.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 1801; 3.0 p. fragment; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 1804; 4.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
    The date of this letter is taken from the notes of a previous archivist.
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 1802-1803; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 8 June 1804; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Hannah Foulke, 21 December 1804; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 3 August 1804; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Owen Jones, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 2 August 1800; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - Poetry by Elizabeth Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 1784; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - Poetry by Elizabeth Wister, 18 December 1793; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - Poetry by Elizabeth Wister, 1804; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to John Wister, 1794; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - Poetry by Elizabeth Wister, 12 April 1801; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - Poetry by Elizabeth Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 1803; 2.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 1804; 4.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 10 July 1803; 3.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - Record of an Affair, 1785-1786; 14.0 p.; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 1804; 4.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
    The date is taken from a note left by a previous archivist.
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 1805; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
    The date of this letter is taken from a note by a previous archivist.
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 1805; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
    The of this letter is taken from a note by a previous archivist.
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 10 July 1807; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 11 September 1812; 7.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 3 September; 4.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 24 December 1803; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 29 July 1814; 5.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Rebecca Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 19 August 1807; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 6 August 1845; 4.0 p.; Wister, Hannah Lewis,
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 8 February 1830; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah Lewis,
  - ALS to William W. Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Hannah Lewis,
  - ALS to William W. Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Hannah Lewis,
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 18 February 1830; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah Lewis,
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 14 June 1842; 3.0 p.; Wister, Hannah Lewis,
  - ALS to Mr. Doolittle, 1929; 1.0 p.; Wister, James W.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 1 July 1802; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
    Recipient
    This letter is not addressed and did not come with an envelope. The author does refer to "My dear little Sarah". The recipient probably Sarah Wister.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 8 July 1802; 1.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
    This letter is addressed to Eliza H. Wister. In the letter she is referred to as Betsy and her full name is Elizabeth H. Wister.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 15 July 1802; 1.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
    This letter is addressed to Eliza H. Wister. In the letter she is referred to as Betsy and her full name is Elizabeth H. Wister
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 16 July 1802; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 28 February 1806; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 24 February; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 26 February; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 2 June 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 1 June 1819; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 26 January 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 27 January 1819; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 19 May 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 29 May 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 5 June 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 28 January 1822; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 22 May 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 29 May 1819; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to Elizabeth H. Wister, 17 February 1826; 3.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to G. Thayer, 6 May 1833; 8 February 1834; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
  - ALS to George Wlioss, 3 August 1825; 2.0 p.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
    The characters of the recipient are unclear and should be examined again.
  - ALS to John Wister, March 1832; 4.0 p. Contains two different pieces.; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.
    This letter appears to be from John Wister to himself about finicial affiars.
  - ALS to Wister Grandchildren, 22 December 1777; 3.0 p. Contains a original and two copies of one letter.; Wister, John Sr.
  - ALS to Wister Grandchildren, 6 July 1777; 2.0 p.; Wister, John Sr.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 15 October 1837; 1.0 p.; Wister, Jones
  - ALS to Sarah (Sally) Wister, undated; 4.0 p.; Wister, Lily T.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, May 1801; 2.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS to Charles Wister, October 1798; 2.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS Hannah Foulke, 23 March 1803; 3.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS to Hannah Foulke, 28 November 1802; 3.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS to Charles & William W. Wister, 25 May 1797; 4.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 10 January 1790; 2.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS to Owen Jones, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 16 January 1800; 3.0 p.; Wister, Lowry
  - Account by Wister, Lowry, 16 August 1778; 8 p. Fragmenting
  - ALS to Sarah E. Wister, 19 February 1848; 2.0 p.; Wister, Owen J., (Owen Jones), 1825-1896
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 16 June 1843; 2.0 p.; Wister, Owen J., (Owen Jones), 1825-1896
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 15 February 1849; 4.0 p.; Wister, Owen J., (Owen Jones), 1825-1896
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 11 June 1849; 4.0 p.; Wister, Owen J., (Owen Jones), 1825-1896
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 26 January 1850; 4.0 p.; Wister, Owen J., (Owen Jones), 1825-1896
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 16 September 1842; 4.0 p.; Wister, Susan
  - ALS to Charles Wister Jr., 4 October 1842; 4.0 p.; Wister, Susan
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 2 August 1839; 3.0 p.; Wister, Susan
  - ALS to Susan Sparklin, 28 March; 2.0 p.; Wister, Rebecca
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 1812; 4.0 p.; Wister, Rebecca
  - ALS to Wister Brothers, 17 September 1862; 4.0 p.; Wister, Rachel
  - ALS to Issac Pennington, 24 May 1800; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 14 July 1796; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 19 August 1796; 1.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to William Wister, 1781; 1.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Copy Silhouette of Wister, Sarah, undated; 2.0 p. Contains a document describing the silhouette.
  - ALS to Hannah Foulke, 20 January 1802; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Owen Jones, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Rebecca Bullock, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 14 August 1795; 4.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Sarah (Sally) Wister, 21 October 1783; 3.0 p.
    The author of this letter is unknown.
  - ALS to Hannah Foulke, 31 May 1803; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 8 September 1796; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Owen Jones, 4 July 1797; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Elizabeth Wister, undated; 4.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, 1791; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, undated; 4.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Charles Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, undated; 1.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, 30 July 1792; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, 1790; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, 21 January 1796; 4.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, 29 December 1793; 4.0 p. Originally one piece of paper with writing on both sides, but the document has fragmented into two pieces.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Dr. George Bensell, July 1793; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Charles Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - Poetry by Wister, Sarah, 1 July 1791; 1.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
    This piece of poetry is signed Laura, which was the nom de plume of Sarah Wister.
  - ALS to Hannah Foulke, undated; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 3 September 1848; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah E.
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 9 August 1845; 2.0 p.; Wister, Sarah E.
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 25 August 1844; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah E.
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 3 September 1845; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah E.
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 28 February 1848; 4.0 p.; Wister, Sarah E.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 2 July 1844; 3.0 p.; Wister, Sarah Whitesides
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 25 December 1805; 2.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 29 March 1802; 3.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 28 January 1802; 3.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 28 July 1802; 3.0; Wister, William Wynne
  - ALS to Susan Foulke, 18 February 1803; 3.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne
  - ALS to Charles Wister Jr., 2 March 1830; 3.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne
  - ALS to Mrs. William W. Wister, 3 July 1867; 1.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne Jr.
  - ALS to Mrs. William W. Wister, 10 July 1869; 1.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne Jr.
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 16 August 1845; 1.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne Jr.
  - ALS to William W. Wister Jr., undated; 2.0 p.; Wister, Mrs. William Wynne
  - ALS to William W. Wister Jr., 18 September 1862; 2.0 p.; Wister, Mrs. William Wynne
- Bound Volumes
  - Medical recipes of Wister, Lowry, undated
  - Bees by Wister, Charles, 16 June 1824- 29 August 1827; No.1; 21.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Memoranda by Wister, Charles, 1820; No.2; 36.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Agricultural Memorandums and Experiments by Wister Charles Sr. and Jr., 1806-1878; No.3; 116.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Scarps of Rhyme by Wister, Charles, 1804; No.4; 60.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Diary of a trip to Pittsburgh by Wister, Charles, 1812; No.5; 45.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
    Summary
    C.J.W.'s trip to Pittsburg, May 1812. Rebecca Bullock, daugther of Joseph Bullock, on account of whose poor health (Consumption?) the was made, died, shortly after, -September, 1812. She was his first wife.
  - Diary of a trip to Niagara Falls by Wister, Charles, 1815; No.6; 38.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Recipes and Directions by Wister, Charles, 4 August 1854; No.7; 30.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - Photographs of Grumblethorpe, etc. by Wister, Charles Jr., 1843-1860; No.8; 5.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
    Enclosed are early photographs of "Grumblethorpe" by C.J.W., Jr., taken by the daguerre process, silver on copper, invented in 1839. Photography was then in its infancy, and C.J.W. was one of the earlist experimenters in the city. One of the plates is dated 1843, and is probably the fist photograph ever taken of the house. The one framed in paper, 1848, shows the improvement of five years practice. The old observatory, taken in 1858, shows even greater skill. Enclosed with the pictures are several unexposed samples of daguerre plates. (Missing?)
  - Notes by Wister, Charles Jr., 9 April 1865; No.9; 30.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Diary of Wister, Charles Jr., 1841; No.10; 8.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Diary of Wister, Charles Jr., 1842; No.10; 30.0 p. Contains 3 letters, a diary, and another bound extract.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
    Letters
    Letter 1: ALS to Charles Wister Jr. from Jony Johnson, 3 p., 23 September 1842 Letter 2: ALS to Charles Wister Jr. from Sarah Wister, 4 p., 15 October 1842 Letter 3: ALS to Charles Wister Jr. from W.W.W. Ruschenberger, 2 p., 15 October 1842
  - Diary of Wister, Charles Jr., April 1848; No.10; 34.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Diary of Wister, Charles Jr., October 1854; No.10; 102.0 p. Contains two flowersand photogram.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Diary of Wister, Charles Jr., 1856; No.10; 21.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Diary of Wister, Charles Jr., 1865; No.10; 68.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Record of New Year Eves by Wister, Charles Jr., 1852-1903; No.11; 150.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.
  - Garden Book by Wister, Daniel and Sarah, 1771-1776; No.12; 70.0 p.; Wister, Daniel, 1739-1805; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804
    Daniel Wister's garden book, used by him, 1771-1776, in which he carefully records bulbs and flowers planted in the various beds. Sally (Sarah) Wister then uses it and continues her North Wales diary and other interesting records.
  - Weather Account Book of Wister, William, 1818-1821; No.13; 97.0 p.; Wister, William Wynne
  - Account Book of Lukens, Jesse, 8 June 1773; No.14; 30.0 p.; Lukens, Jesse
  - Notes of Surveys by Lukens, Jesse, 1774; No.15; 31.0 p.; Lukens, Jesse
  - Aitkens' General American Register of Lukens, Jesse, 1773; No.16; 171.0 p.; Lukens, Jesse
  - Poor Will's Almanack with notes by Lukens, John, 1778; No.17; 58.0 p.; Lukens, Jesse
  - Envelope containing letters to/from Lukens, John and Jesse, 1775-1894; No.18; 6.0 p. Contains 5 letters and an envelope
    Letter 1: ALS to John Lukens from Charles Lukens [?], 1 p., 3 January 1776 Letter 2: ALS to Benjamin Parvin from J. Lukens [John or Jesse?], 1 p., undated Letter 3: ALS to John Lukens from Jesse Lukens, 1 p., 5 October 1775 Letter 4: ALS to John Lukens from G. Wallis, 1 p., 6 August 1783 Letter 5: ALS to Lacy Lukens [?] from John Lukens, 1 p., undated